College of Humanities and Social Sciences Records 1913-1999 1960-1989
Carnegie Mellon University
- Departments, This series is arranged in the following Subseries by Department: Economics English History Philosophy Modern Languages Physical Education Political Science Psychology Social Science Statistics Margaret Morrison Carnegie College
  - English
    - English--"The Development of a Sequential and Cumulative Program in English for Able College-Bound Students in the Senior High School, Grades 10 through 12", 1967
    - English--"Final Technical Report on the Institute for Secondary School Teachers of English Grades 10, 11, 12"--Robert C. Slack, 1967
    - English--"Program to Extend Curriculum Materials in English for the Able to a Wider Student Group"--Robert C. Slack, 1967
    - English--"A Summary Plan of the Advanced Placement Course in English for the Pittsburgh Area High Schools During the Years 1961-62", 1962
    - English--"The Overall Plan"--Erwin R. Steinberg, et al., date unknown
    - English--"Structural Signal Words", date unknown
    - English--Guide to Pittsburgh, date unknown
    - English--Project English--9th Grade Book, date unknown
    - English--Project English--9th Grade Course, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Summary Plans, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Reading List, date unknown
    - English--Project English--"Readings in World Literature Volume I", date unknown
    - English--Project English--"Readings in World Literature Volume II", date unknown
    - English--Project English--List of Works Used in 10th grade, 1965-1966
    - English--Curriculum Study Center--"A Tenth Grade Composition Program", 1964
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Comp., 1964
    - English--Curriculum Study Center--"A Tenth Grade Language Program", 1964
    - English--Project English--10th Grade--Intro Unit, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit One--Social Concerns, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Two--Love, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Three--Reality and Illusion, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Four--Heroism, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Five--Human Weakness, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Six--The Search for Wisdom, date unknown
    - English--Curriculum Study Center--"A Tenth Grade Literature Program", 1964
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit One: The America Puritan Attitude, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Two: The American Desire for Success, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Three: American Idealism, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Four: American Darker Spirit, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Five: American Dream Reconsidered, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Six: American Quest for Identity, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Seven: Robert Frost: American Spokesman, date unknown
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Eight: Variation
    - English--Project English--10th Grade Unit Nine: Case and Case Inflection, date unknown
    - English--Project English--11th Grade Summary Plans, date unknown
    - English--Project English--11th Grade Reading List, date unknown
    - English--Curriculum Study Center--"An Eleventh Grade Composition Program", 1964
    - English--Project English--11th Grade Comp, date unknown
    - English--Project English--11th Grade Composition Unit, date unknown
    - English--Project English--11th Grade Language Units, date unknown
    - English--"An Eleventh Grade Literature Program", date unknown
    - English--Project English--"Selections from Puritan Authors", date unknown
    - English--Project English--11th Grade--"American Literature", date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Summary Plans, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Reading List, date unknown
    - English--Project English Grade 12, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Comp, date unknown
    - English--Curriculum Study Center--"A Twelfth Grade Composition Program", 1964
    - English--Curriculum Study Center--"A Twelfth Grade Language Program", 1964
    - English--Project English--Unit III: Lyric Poetry I, date unknown
    - English--Project English--Grade 12, date unknown[2]
    - English--Project English--Unit Six: Lyric Poetry II, date unknown
    - English--Project English--(12) Unit Seven: The Novel, date unknown
    - English--Curriculum Study Center--"A Twelfth grade Literature Program, 1964
    - English--Project English--Booklist--Dr. Slack Victorian Literature, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Unit One: The Tale, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Unit Two: Tragedy, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Unit Three: Lyric Poetry I, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th grade Unit Four: The Epic, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Unit Five: Satire, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Unit Six: Lyric Poetry II, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Unit Seven: The Novel, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade Unit Eight: Social Drama, date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade--"As They Look to the Reader", date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade--"The Nature of Satire", date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade--"Wuthering Heights Chart", date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade--"Tomorrow Tomorrow", date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade--"A Treasury of the Theatre", date unknown
    - English--Project English--Decameron (12), date unknown
    - English--Project English--12th Grade--Beowulf Manuscript, date unknown
    - English--Project English--Metrics and Verse Form (Day 99), date unknown
  - History
    - History—Correspondence, 1989
    - History—Annual Report, 1949-1954
    - History—Annual Report, 1955-1960
    - History—Annual Report, 1961-1962
    - History—Annual Report, 1962-1963
    - History—Annual Report, 1963-1964
    - History—Annual Report, 1964-1965
    - History—Annual Report, 1965-1966
    - History—Annual Report, 1966-1967
    - History—Annual Report, 1967-1968
    - History—Annual Report, 1968-1969
    - History—Annual Report, 1969-1970
    - History—Annual Report, 1970-1971
    - History—Annual Report, 1971-1972
    - History—Annual Report, 1972-1973
    - History—Annual Report, 1973-1974
    - History—Annual Report, 1974-1975
    - History—Annual Report, 1975-1976
    - History—Annual Report, 1976-1977
    - History—Annual Report, 1977-1978
    - History—Annual Report, 1978-1979
    - History—Annual Report, 1979-1980
    - History—Annual Report, 1980-1981
    - History—Annual Report, 1981-1982
    - History—Annual Report, 1982-1983
    - History—Annual Report, 1983-1984
    - History—Annual Report, 1984-1985
    - History—Annual Report, 1986-1987
    - History—Old Vitae
    - History—Ambrose, Susan
    - History—Barnes, A. E.
    - History—Chapman, Herrick
    - History—Cohen, Lizabeth
    - History—Constant, E. W.
    - History—Eden, Lynn R.
    - History—Fenton, E.
    - History—Fowler, D. H.
    - History—Goldman, Wendy Z.
    - History—Hounshell, D.
    - History—Kaiser, D. E.
    - History—Langer, Erick D.
    - History—Lazarus, Barbara
    - History—Levy, E. D.
    - History—Lindemann, Mary
    - History—Lynch, K. A.
    - History—Miller, D. W.
    - History—Modell, John
    - History—Modell, Judith
    - History—Modell, Judith[2]
    - History—Resnick, D. P.
    - History—Schoenwald, R. L.
    - History—Stearns, Peter N.
    - History—Schlossman, Steven
    - History—Trotter, Joe William, Jr.
    - History—New Proposals--Data-Forms, 1988-1991
    - History—Proposals—New Submitted, 1991
    - History—"Enriching Modern Language and Humanities Through Content Based Instruction", 1991
    - History—Publications--"Carnegie Mellon Magazine", 1991
    - History—Senior Thesis Pamphlet, date unknown
    - History—Graduate Programs in History, date unknown
    - History—Graduate Studies, date unknown
    - History—Doctor of Arts in History, date unknown
    - History—Graduate Brochure, date unknown
    - History—Undergraduate Brochure, date unknown
    - History--Annual Reports, 1970-1978
    - History/Philosophy--Goals Statement, 1972
    - History--Department Statistics, 1975-1985
    - History/Philosophy--Evaluation Committee Report, 1976-1977
    - History/Philosophy--Evaluation Committee Report, 1976-1977[2]
    - History--Visiting Committee, 1990
    - History/Philosophy--Review Committee, 1984
    - History--Department Advisory Council, 1995
    - History--Department Head Evaluation, 1977
    - History--Department Head Evaluation, 1977[2]
    - History--Teaching History, 1958-1959
    - History--Lecture Series, 1967
    - History--Cooperative Program Proposal, 1966
    - Faculty--History/Philosophy--Teaching Loads, 1967-1983
    - History--Faculty List, 1970-1971
    - History--Faculty, 1974-1976
    - History/Philosophy--Faculty List, date unknown
    - History--History and Philosophy Faculty Breakdown, 1973
    - History--Schoenwald, Richard--Memorial Service, 1995
    - History--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1950-1963
    - History--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1966-1970
    - History--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1977-1982
    - History--Faculty--General Correspondence, 1984-1987
    - History--Faculty--General Correspondence, date unknown
    - History--Course Offerings, 1949-1950
    - History--Course Offerings, 1966-1971
    - History--Course Offerings, 1971-1975
    - History--Course Offerings, 1978-1979
    - History--Course Offerings, 1982
    - History--Course Offerings, 1994-1995
    - History--Course Offerings, date unknown
    - History--Graduate Program--Goals Statement, date unknown
    - History--Graduate Program--Admissions Requirements, 1975-1978
    - History--Graduate Program--Graduate Committee Meeting Minutes, 1967-1970
    - History--Graduate Program--Endowment Requests, 1979
    - History--Graduate Program--Student List, 1969
    - History--Graduate Program--Doctor of Arts in History, date unknown
    - History--Graduate Course Offerings, 1967-1971
    - History--"Graduate Study in History for Community and Two-Year College History and Social Sciences Instructors", date unknown
    - History--Graduate Program Correspondence, 1966-1985
    - History--Graduate Program--Applied History and Social Science--Annual Report, 1978-1979
    - History--Graduate Program--Applied History and Social Science, 1975
    - History--Graduate Program--Applied History and Social Science, 1975[2]
    - History--Graduate Program--Applied History and Social Science, 1976-1981
    - History--Graduate Program--Applied History and Social Science--Pamphlets, date unknown
    - History--Summer Foreign Language Program, 1981
    - History--"Majoring in History at MMCC", 1960-1961
    - History--History Committee on Teaching Evaluation, 1969
    - History--Summer Institute, 1967-1969
    - History--Cooperative Program in History, 1968-1969
    - History--Gilmore, Allen--"Method is the Bond", 1951
    - History--Gilmore, Allen--"The Methods and Concepts of History", 1952
    - History--Memoranda, 1963-1967
    - Philosophy--Krieger, Martin, 1976
    - Philosophy--Visiting Committee Report, 1976
    - History--Pamphlets on Graduate Studies, date unknown
    - History--Graduate Study Brochures, date unknown
    - History--Civil War Correspondence, [1863]
    - History--Faculty and Grad Student Address Lists, 1981-1989
    - History Dept., 1966
    - History--CMU History Workshop--Dave Miller, 1979
    - History Political Science--Annual Report, 1924-1925
    - History Political Science--Annual Report, 1925-1926
    - History--Brochure--History Forum, 1988
    - History--Brochure--Annual Report, 1987
    - History--Newsclippings, 1983
    - History--Course Announcements Related Material, 1987
    - History--Correspondence and Memorandums, 1988
    - History--Application Instructions, date unknown
    - History--History Graduate Student Addresses, 1988
    - History--Announcements--Conferences and Lectures, 1980-1987
    - History--The First Biennial Conference on Social History, 1988
    - History--Grad Meetings, 1988
    - History--Colloquium in Applied History and Public Policy, 1988
    - History--Newsclippings, 1986
    - History--Brochure--"Technical Leaflet", 1980
    - History—Pamphlets--Fellowships in History, date unknown
    - History—NDEA Summer Institute in History, 1966-1970
    - History—EPDA Summer Institute, 1969
    - History—Technology and Humanities, 1975
    - History—Graduate Catalogs, 1975
    - History—Memorandum--Promoting Academic Integrity at CMU, 1986
    - History—Project Social Studies—Progress Reports, 1963-1967
    - History—Project Social Studies—Project and Course Outlines, date unknown
    - History—Journal of Social History—Invoice, date unknown
    - History—Project Social Studies—Correspondence and Press Releases, date unknown
    - History—Project Social Studies—Journal Articles, 1964
    - History—Project on Social History—Unit 1, Lesson 5, date unknown
    - History—Research in Social History at CMU—Transparencies, date unknown
    - History--"Teaching United States History with the Great American History Machine"--David W. Miller and John Modell, 1988
    - History—Application for Graduate Study, date unknown
    - History—Flyers, date unknown
    - History—Memoranda, Inter-Office Correspondence, 1989
    - History--"The History Newsletter", 1990
    - History—Project on Social History—Teacher's Guide—Social History of the Family, 1980
    - History—Project on Social History—Teacher's Guide—The History of Childhood, 1980
    - History—Project on Social History—Teacher's Guide--"Crime and Law Enforcement in History", 1980
    - History—Project on Social History—Newsletter—Update, 1981
    - History—Advanced Placement History Conference—Memorandum, Programs, Rosters, Ledger, date unknown
    - History—Teacher Training Leadership Plans, 1969-1970
    - History—"Majoring in History at Margaret Morrison Carnegie College", 1961
    - History—Cooperative Program in History, 1974
    - History—Newsclipping—Smith, Roland M., 1977
    - History--"Authentic Responses to the Holocaust"--Posters, 1978
    - History—Ward, Paul L.--"A Style of History for Beginners", 1959
    - History—Ward, Paul L.--"Teaching Note Taking to History Students", 1959
    - History—Ellis, George Mark--"Robinson Crusoe: The use of the Novel in a History Course", 1959
    - History—Fenton, Edwin—Teaching the First Ten Assignments in a European History Course, 1959
    - History—Fenton, Edwin—Teaching the Survey Course in American History: College Level, 1959
    - History—Engel, Martin, 1964-1967
    - History—Summer Institute in History--Miscellaneous, 1964
    - History—Summer Institute in History—Reports, 1964-1965
    - History—Strathmeyer, Richard D.--"An Introduction to the History of the United States", 1965
    - History—Summer Institute in History—Director's Report, 1965
    - History—Summer Institute in History—Publicity, 1964-1969
    - History—NDEA Summer Institute for World History—Experienced Teacher Fellowship—Advanced Placement in History Conference, 1965-1970
    - "The Origins of the Turbojet Revolution"--Edward W. Constant II, 1980
    - "The American Mind in the Mid-Nineteenth Century"--Irving H. Bartlett, 1967
    - "Student Text for Crime and Law Enforcement in History"--Joanne Furtek, 1980
    - "Student Text for Crime and Law Enforcement in History"--Joanne Furtek, 1980[2]
    - "Student Text for the Family in History"--Charles L. Hill, 1980
    - "Student Text for the History of Childhood in Western Europe and the United States 1630-1980"--A. Lenore Schneider
    - Journal of Social History--"Special Issue on Applied History", 1981
    - Journal of Social History--"Special Issue on Applied History", 1981[2]
    - "The New Social Studies for the Slow Learner"--Edwin Fenton, 1969
    - "Urbanization in Africa: A Resource Unit", 1970
    - History and Philosophy—Annual Report, 1976-1977
    - History—Course Descriptions, 1989
    - Philosophy Department—HSS—Annual Report, 1973-1974
    - History—Annual Report, 1970-1971
    - History and Philosophy—Annual Report—Publications, 1972-1973
    - History and Philosophy—Annual Report—Faculty Activities, 1972-1973
    - History—Letters to Graduate Students, 1988
    - History Dept.--Papers--Natasha Anderson--"The Great Migration to Pittsburgh: Emerging Class Differences Among Blacks as Evidenced by the Pittsburgh Courier", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Darlene V. W. Alling--"The Mon Valley Unemployed Committee; It’s Rallies, Protests, and Support for Pittsburgh’s Unemployed Steel Workers, 1982-1983", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Leslie D. Baltic--"The Forging of Society: An Analysis of Iron and Steel Industrialization in Lorraine, France and Western Pennsylvania", 1993
    - History Dept.--Papers--Rachel Batch--""A Profile of the Free Black Community in Pittsburgh, 1850", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Robert S. Berthold--"Industry, Labor, and Social Change on the Hill in Pittsburgh, 1899-1919", date unknown
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jacqueline M. Biello--"Reporting the Holocaust: What People in Pittsburgh Knew About the Atrocities in Europe, 1933-1995"
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jessica Lillian Bier--"A Socio-Historical Study: The Sudden Rise of Unitarianism in Pittsburgh, 1890-1900", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Cheryl Brewer--Seminar Paper, date unknown
    - History Dept.--Papers--Christy Callahan--"Some Men Learn Enough In One Trip to Europe to Bore Their Friends for Life: The European Travel Culture of the Pittsburgh Elite, 1900-1910", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jessica Chalifoux--"Women’s Educational Efforts in Greater Pittsburgh, 1900-1930", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Dong Chung--"Women in Late Nineteenth Century Pittsburgh-Views of Women and Gender Roles in Pittsburgh Newspapers Between 1870 through the 1890’s", 1993
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jill Paula Christy--"The Amish of New Wilmington and Volant", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Alexei J. Cohen--"Anti-War Resistance: A Tale of Two Universities", date unknown
    - History Dept.--Papers--David B. Conklin--"The Relationship Between the German Community and Pittsburgh During the First World War", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Ria David--"Change in Women Heads of Establishment in Ireland, 1800-1850", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Dana C. Del Bianco--""Kiss It Goodbye: The Effects of the Closing of Forbes Field on Baseball in Pittsburgh", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Roberta Draper--"Pittsburgh’s Committed Suffragette’s and Their Fight for Political Emancipation", 1993
    - History Dept.--Papers--Melissa Economy--"The Development of the Film Industry in Pittsburgh", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Hollie R. Erdelyi--"Life in North Braddock, 1920-1930", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Daniel E. Fiore--"A Flowering Glimpse of Heaven: An Analysis of Nineteenth Century Children’s Epitaphs in Western Pennsylvania, 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Ezra Charles Fowler--"Build It and They Will Fund: The History of Stadium Financing for the Pittsburgh Pirates Baseball Franchise", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Dennis A. Frey, Jr.--"Pittsburgh Opinion on U.S. Native American Policy, 1795-1830", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jennifer L. Geller--"Selling the Symphony: Transformation of the Working World of the Symphony Musician by Pittsburgh’s Business Class in the Pittsburgh Orchestra, 1900-1910", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--Marcy Auralias Gibbons--"Seminar Paper", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Michael Goettsche--"The Decline of Soccer in Pittsburgh, 1910-1930", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Thomas Greene--"A Torch to Dry Fields", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--P. Charles Hachten--"The Presbyterian Banner and the Rhetoric of Pleasure Seeking, 1869-1881", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Mary Beth Healey--’Pittsburgh Women and the Red Cross During World War II", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Micheal Hession--The Pittsburgh Renaissance; Specifically the Lower Hill Redevelopment and It’s Social Ramifications on the Black Community of the Hill District", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jeff Hinkleman--"East Pittsburgh: Early History of an Industrial Community", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Christy Lynn Hipchen--"Sin and the City: Social Structures and Brothels in Pittsburgh in 1880", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Matt Horgan--"Blood Sport in Pittsburgh: An Analysis of Prize Fighting and Cock Fighting in an American Industrial City", date unknown
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jonathan Hurshman--"Pittsburgh Catholics and Vichy France", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Heather Jacobson--"The Nixon Theater", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--Lawenda (Wendy) James--"The Two Faces of Eve: Media Treatments of Women in Pittsburgh, 1989-1850", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Darren Kastin--"A Jewish Community in Industrialization Pittsburgh: 1914", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Seth J. Kaufman--"Rock ‘n’ Roll Music: A Look at Some of the Social Roles of Music, In Particular Rock and Roll Music, in Two Pittsburgh High Schools from 1960 to 1965", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Matt Kelly--"The Irish Participation in the Pittsburgh Police Department, 1870-1917", 1993
    - History Dept.--Papers--Michael Kenny--"Transitions in the Pittsburgh Retail Grocery Trade: 1920-1950", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Lubimor W. Krochanskyj--"Professional Baseball in Pittsburgh During the Early War Years (1941-1942)", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jennifer Kratt--"Making Order Out of Chaos: The Italian American Experience of World War II", 1991
    - History Dept.--Papers--Alexis M. Landeros--"The Growth of the Pittsburgh Arts Through the Generosity of Sarah Sciafe", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--John H. Lee--"Democratic Leveling Up of Mass Intelligence", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Brendan P. McFeeley--"Newspapers, Unions, and Pittsburgh: THe Newspaper Strike of 1950", date unknown
    - History Dept.--Papers--Barbara McQuain--"Jewels in a City’s Crown: The Pittsburgh Concert Scene", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Helen McRae--"The Integration of Women into the Carnegie Mellon University: The Legacy of Margaret Morrison Carnegie College", 1992
    - History Dept.--Papers--Maciej Matyjas--"Political Participation in the 1849 Municipal Elections: The Role of Germans and Connections", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Katie Maynard--"The Woods Run Settlement Home: Similarities with and Divergences from National and Regional Norms", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Chris Mega--"Pennsylvania Sportsmen and Wild Conservation, 1870-1920", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Arch L. Moberly, Jr.--"Supportive Families in the Civil War", 1995
    - History Dept.--Papers--Christy M. Moore--"Out with the Old-What is the New?-Administrative Decisions and the Student Reactions at Carnegie Mellon University, 1966-1970", 1993
    - History Dept.--Papers--Jill Moore--"Socioeconomic Change in Homestead and Its Effects on Women: The Influence of the Decline of the Homestead Works, 1950-1980", 1990
    - History Dept.--Papers--Steve Moyer--"Humanity in Pittsburgh, 1880-1930", 1996
    - History Dept.--Papers--Ian Murphy--"Pittsburgh’s Response to the Cholera Epidemic of 1832-1833", 1996